Guide to the Norris Houghton Papers, 1915-1998
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Norris Houghton Papers
1915-1998
Houghton, Norris
15.75 cubic feet (28 boxes, 18 reels)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence, manuscripts, typescripts, playbills, contracts, clippings, photographs, and memorabilia documenting the life and theatrical career of Norris Houghton.
Biographical Note
Norris Houghton was born in Indianapolis, Indiana, on December 26, 1909. After graduation from Princeton University in 1931, Houghton began a long career as a theatrical designer, producer, and director. That career encompassed both the New York stage and regional theaters throughout the United States, as well as extended professional visits to Western Europe, the Soviet Union, and East Asia. In 1953 he founded, with T. Edward Hambleton, the Phoenix Theatre, one of the first and most successful of New York City's Off- Broadway theaters. Also a noted teacher and scholar of theater, Norris Houghton held academic positions at several colleges and universities. In 1962 Houghton joined the Drama Department of Vassar College, serving until 1967 as department chair and director of the Vassar Experimental Theatre. Norris Houghton died in October 2001.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, manuscripts, typescripts, playbills, contracts, clippings, photographs, and memorabilia documenting the life and theatrical career of Norris Houghton.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Vassar College Drama Department Records
Subject Headings
Names:
Bundy, McGeorge; Hambleton, T. Edward, 1911-2005; Mucha, Jiří, 1915-1991; Redgrave, Michael, Sir
Organizations:
Phoenix Theatre (Organization: New York, N.Y.); Experimental Theatre of Vassar College
Subjects:
Theater--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Theater--Soviet Union
Document Types:
Photographic prints
VCL Categories
Theater, Drama and Film
Encoding Information
Encoded by Mark Seidl, February-March 2012.
Acquisition Information
The bulk of this collection was aquired in March 2003 (M2003-008), with additions in March 2006 (M2006-003), June 2009 (M2009-012), and March 2011 (M2011-014). All of the material was the gift of Frank L. Dent.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The audio tapes and films in Series VIII will need to be duplicated at the researcher's expense before use.
Series List
- Series I. Correspondence, 1915-1998
  Divided into two subseries, this series includes Norris Houghton's extensive correspondence with his mother, Grace Houghton, as well as his personal and professional correspondence. Correspondents include U. S. National Security Advisor McGeorge Bundy, theatrical producor T. Edward Hambleton, Czech writer Jiří Mucha, and several noted actors. This series has been left largely in original order. Material is foldered in original groupings, but the folders have been arranged chronologically.
- Series II. Writings, 1930-1993
  This series is divided into four subseries. The first includes Norris Hougton's college essays and is arranged chronologically. The second subseries includes manuscripts and typescripts of and reviews and publicity materials for the following books and is arranged chronologically by the publication date of each book: Moscow Rehersals (1936), Advance From Broadway (1941), But Not Forgotten (1951), Return Engagement (1962), The Exploding Stage (1971), and Entrances and Exits (1991). The third subseries consists of Norris Hougton's articles published in a variety of magazines and is arranged alphabetically. The forth subseries, arranged alphabetically, includes miscellaneous writings.
- Series III. Addresses and Lectures, 1960-1993
  This series includes drafts and typescritps of and research materials for Norris Houghtons public addresses and lectures. The series is arranged chronologically.
- Series IV. Contracts, 1930-1981
  This series consists of Norris Houghton's contracts for a variety of theatrical work, including direction and set design. The series is arranged chronologically.
- Series V. Subject Files, 1946-1994
  Divided into eight subseries, this series includes materials pertaining to the academic institutions with which Norris Hougton was affiliated, the arts and theater education foundations of which he was a memeber, the awards committees on which he sat, the conferences in which he participated, and the honor societies to which he belonged. Also included are files of family and personal documents and materials concerning miscellaneous subjects. Of particular interest are the files of materials pertaining to the theaters and theatrical productions with which Norris Houghton was involved. Each subseries is arranged alphbetically.
- Series VI. Clippings and Printed Materials, 1927-circa 1981; (Some materials in this series are very fragile. See container list below.)
  This series consists of newspaper clippings, theater posters, programs and playbills, copies of Life Magazine, working scripts, and other printed matter. The series is arranged alphabetically.
- Series VII. Photographic Materials, circa 1915-1986
  This series is divided into four subseries. The first consists of formal and informal photographs of Norris Houghton, the second of stage productions he designed or directed, and the third of Russian performers and productions from the 1960s to the early 1970s. The final subseries consists of miscellaneous photographs.
- Series VIII. Audio-Visual Materials
  The first of two subseries in this series includes audio tapes devoted to several actors and to "Aspects of the Contemporary American Theater," a lecture Norris Houghton delivered in Italy. The second subseries consists of motion-picture films of productions by the Phoenix Theatre and of "Playwrights in the Contemporary Theater," a television program to which Norris Houghton contributed. Both subseries are arranged alphabetically. The film and tape in this series require duplication at the researcher's expense before use.
- Series IX. Memorabilia, 1934-1991
  This series includes date and address books, awards certificates, honorary diplomas, scrap- and souvenier books, and other memorabilia.
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Letters to Grace Houghton
    - 1915-1931 (Box 1)
    - 1931-1964 (Box 2)
  - Personal and Professional Correspondence
    - 1926-1930 (Folder 3.1)
    - 1949 (Folder 3.2)
    - 1949-1950 (Folder 3.3)
    - 1949-1951 (Folder 3.4)
    - 1949-1951 (Folder 3.5)
    - circa 1950-1951 (Folder 3.6)
    - 1953-1958 (Folder 3.7)
    - 1953-1959 (Folder 3.8)
    - 1956 (Folder 3.9)
    - 1958-1959 (Folder 3.10)
    - 1958-1961 (Folder 3.11)
    - 1960-1961 (Folder 3.12)
    - 1960-1962 (Folder 3.13)
    - 1961-1962 (Folder 3.14)
    - 1961-1963 (Folder 3.15)
    - 1962-1963 (Folder 3.16)
    - 1964-1966 (Folder 3.17)
    - 1967-1969 (Folder 3.18)
    - 1970-1972 (Folder 3.19)
    - 1973-1975 (Folder 3.20)
    - 1976-1979 (Folder 3.21)
    - 1980-1998 (Folder 3.22)
    - 1990-1992 (Folder 3.23)
- Series II: Writings
  - College Essays
    - "The Women of Thomas Hardy's Novels,", 1930 (Folder 4.1)
    - "The Intime... Ten Years After,", 1931 (Folder 4.2)
  - Books
    - Moscow Rehersals - reviews (England) (Folder 4.3)
    - Moscow Rehersals - reviews (USA) (Folder 4.4)
    - Advance From Broadway - reviews (Folder 4.5)
    - But Not Forgotten - reviews and promotional material (Folder 4.6)
    - Return Engagement - incomplete draft (Folder 4.7)
    - Return Engagement [Their Life In Art] - typescript (Folder 4.8)
    - Return Engagement - typescript (Box 17)
    - Return Engagement - proofs (Folder 4.9)
    - Return Engagement - press releases and reviews (Folder 4.10)
    - The Exploding Stage - correspondence and reviews (Folder 4.11)
    - Entrances and Exits - manuscript drafts (Folder 4.12)
    - Entrances and Exits - manuscript drafts (Folder 4.13)
    - Entrances and Exits - manuscript drafts (Folder 4.14)
    - Entrances and Exits - "Advance From Broadway" (Folder 4.15)
    - Entrances and Exits - "Back To Broadway 1935-1940" (Folder 4.16)
    - Entrances and Exits - "Beginnings" (Folder 4.17)
    - Entrances and Exits - "Entr' Acte – To The Continent" (Folder 4.18)
    - Entrances and Exits - "A Fresh Start (1962-67)" (Folder 4.19)
    - Entrances and Exits - "From One Art To Many" (Folder 5.1)
    - Entrances and Exits - Index (Folder 5.2)
    - Entrances and Exits - "Once Again [Farewell] To Broadway]" (Folder 5.3)
    - Entrances and Exits - "Other Worlds (1962-67)" (Folder 5.4)
    - Entrances and Exits - "Other Worlds (1962-67)" (Folder 5.5)
    - Entrances and Exits - "Overture" (Folder 5.6)
    - Entrances and Exits - "The Phoenix Years" (Folder 5.7)
    - Entrances and Exits - "The Purchase Challenge (1967-80)" (Folder 5.8)
    - Entrances and Exits - "The Purchase Challenge (1967-80)" (Folder 5.9)
    - Entrances and Exits - "The Purchase Challenge (1967-80)" (Folder 5.10)
    - Entrances and Exits - "To Broadway" (Folder 5.11)
    - Entrances and Exits - "To Moscow" (Folder 5.12)
    - Entrances and Exits - "To Western Europe" (Folder 5.13)
    - Entrances and Exits - "Transfer To Academe" (Folder 5.14)
    - Entrances and Exits - "Unexpected Interlude: To Britain" (Folder 5.15)
    - Entrances and Exits - "University Players: Baltimore" (Folder 5.16)
    - Entrances and Exits - "University Players: Falmouth (1931)" (Folder 5.17)
    - Entrances and Exits - Chapters 1-2 (Folder 5.18)
    - Entrances and Exits - Chapter 4 (Folder 5.19)
    - Entrances and Exits - unidentified drafts (Folder 5.20)
    - Entrances and Exits - uncorrected proofs, 1990 (Box 27)
    - Entrances and Exits - mailing lists (Folder 5.21)
    - Entrances and Exits - promotional materials (Folder 5.22)
    - Entrances and Exits - promotional materials and reviews (Folder 6.1)
  - Articles
    - "The American Theatre – Today and Tomorrow,", 1964 (Folder 6.2)
    - articles, 1936-1982 (Folder 6.3)
    - articles, 1983-1989 (Folder 6.4)
    - book review, [n.d.] (Folder 6.5)
    - "Characteristics And Development Of The Off-Broadway Theatre Movement,", 1963 (Folder 6.6)
    - "It's A Woman's World,", [n.d.] (Folder 6.7)
    - "Laurette Taylor,", [n.d.] (Folder 6.8)
    - "Rosamond Gilder,", 1994 (Folder 6.9)
    - "Shanghai 1984,", [n.d.] (Folder 6.10)
    - "That Was Yalta,", 1953-1984 (Folder 6.11)
  - Miscellaneous Writings
    - autobiography materials (Folder 6.12)
    - "Introduction" (Folder 6.13)
    - "Memorandum On The Function And Operation Of Theatre For Drama In Lincoln Center,", 1964 (Folder 6.14)
    - obituaries and tributes (Folder 6.15)
    - unidentified manuscript material (Folder 6.16)
    - "Van Druten, John (William),", 1991-1993 (Folder 6.17)
- Series III: Addresses And Lectures
  - Moscow lectures, 1960 (Folder 6.18)
  - Oxford lecture, 1962 (Folder 6.19)
  - Fellows Lecture, 1981 (Folder 6.20)
  - Fellows Lecture, 1981 (Folder 6.21)
  - Fellows Lecture research, 1961-1993 (Folder 6.22)
  - addresses, 1984-1992 (Folder 6.23)
- Series IV: Contracts
  - 1930-1950 (Folder 6.24)
  - 1951-1981 (Folder 6.25)
- Series V: Subject Files
  - Academic Institutions
    - California Institute of the Arts Accreditation, 1981 (Folder 6.26)
    - Columbia University Program in Arts Administration, 1980-1981 (Folder 6.27)
    - Miami University Doctor of Fine Arts, 1991 (Folder 6.28)
    - Pennsylvania State University Visiting Committee, 1963 (Folder 6.29)
    - Princeton University, 1929-1956 (Folder 7.1)
    - State University of New York College at Purchase, 1966-circa 1975 (Folder 7.2)
    - State University of New York College at Purchase, 1976-1988 (Folder 7.3)
    - State University of New York College at Purchase – personal, 1966-1975 (Folder 7.4)
    - State University of New York College at Purchase – planning papers, 1968-circa 1975 (Folder 7.5)
    - University of Louisville, 1977-1983 (Folder 7.6)
    - University of Louisville – visiting committee, 1980-1981 (Folder 7.7)
    - University of Louisville – visiting committee, 1982-1984 (Folder 7.8)
    - Vassar College, 1963-1966 (Folder 7.9)
    - Vassar College, 1982-1985 (Folder 7.10)
    - Yale Residential College Seminars, 1970-1972 (Folder 7.11)
  - Arts and Theatre Education Organizations
    - "The 1980 Meeting On The Arts," (Folder 7.12)
    - American Council for the Arts, 1985 (Folder 7.13)
    - American Council on the Arts in Education, 1969-1977 (Folder 7.14)
    - Arts, Education, and Americans, 1975-1977 (Folder 7.15)
    - Arts, Education, and Americans, circa 1979 (Folder 7.16)
    - Arts, Education, and Americans, 1980 (Folder 7.17)
    - Arts, Education, and Americans, 1980 (Folder 7.18)
    - Arts, Education, and Americans, 1980 (Folder 7.19)
    - Arts, Education, and Americans, 1981 (Folder 8.1)
    - Arts, Education, and Americans, 1981 (Folder 8.2)
    - Arts, Education, and Americans, 1981 (Folder 8.3)
    - Arts, Education, and Americans, 1982 (Folder 8.4)
    - Arts, Education, and Americans, 1985 (Folder 8.5)
    - Arts, Education, and Americans (Folder 8.6)
    - JDR3rd Fund / Rockefeller Foundation, 1966 (Folder 8.7)
    - National Council of the Arts in Education, 6th National Conference Proceedings, 1967 (Folder 8.8)
    - Performing Arts Education Advisory Commission, 1970-1975 (Folder 8.9)
    - theater education materials, 1946-1962 (Folder 8.10)
    - Young Audiences, 1987 (Folder 8.11)
  - Awards Committees
    - OBIE Committee, 1986-1987 (Folder 8.12)
    - Tony Awards Committee, 1981-1985 (Folder 8.13)
    - Tony Award Nominations, 1981-1986 (Folder 8.14)
  - Conferences and Symposia
    - Andover Conference, 1962-1963 (Folder 8.15)
    - Conference on International Exchanges in the Arts, 1970 (Folder 8.16)
    - Conference on Relationships Between Educational and Professional Theatre, 1966 (Folder 8.17)
    - National Theatre Conference, 1983-1984 (Folder 8.18)
    - Stanislavski Symposium, 1988 (Folder 9.1)
    - Symposium on the Arts in Asia, 1978 (Folder 9.2)
    - Wingspread Conference on Theatre and Society, 1975 (Folder 9.3)
  - Family and Personal Materials
    - Houghton, Grace, 1964 (Folder 9.4)
    - family and personal documents (Folder 9.5)
  - Honor Societies
    - Century Association, 1972-1995 (Folder 9.6)
    - Century Association, 1973-1997 (Folder 9.7)
    - College of Fellows of the American Theatre, 1980-1996 (Folder 9.8)
  - Theatres and Theatrical Productions
    - American Kaleidoscope Theatre Company, 1983 (Folder 9.9)
    - "Billy Budd,", 1949-1979 (Folder 9.10)
    - "Candida,", 1952-1972 (Folder 9.11)
    - Carnegie Hall – floor plans, [n.d.] (Folder 9.12)
    - CBS Television Workshop, 1951-1952 (Folder 9.13)
    - Circle Repertory Company, 1975-1981 (Folder 9.14)
    - Circle Repertory Company, 1975-1981 (Folder 9.15)
    - "Classics in Context" / Actors Theatre of Louisville, 1989 (Folder 9.16)
    - Glimmerglass Opera, 1987-1996 (Folder 9.17)
    - Glimmerglass Opera, 1988-1994 (Folder 9.18)
    - Hazel Players, 1988-1990 (Folder 9.19)
    - Heritage Repertory Theatre, 1983 (Folder 9.20)
    - Irving Place Theatre Project, 1952-1954 (Folder 9.21)
    - "Julius Caesar" / Actors Theatre of Louisville, 1982-1983 (Folder 9.22)
    - "Macbeth,", 1947-1948 (Folder 9.23)
    - "Macbeth" / Missouri Repertory Theatre, 1981-1982 (Folder 10.1)
    - "Macbeth" / Missouri Repertory Theatre, 1981-1982 (Folder 10.2)
    - "Misalliance" / Asolo Theatre, 1982-1983 (Folder 10.3)
    - "Misalliance" – text, [n.d.] (Folder 10.4)
    - "The Misanthrope" / Lynchburg College, 1986 (Folder 10.5)
    - National Repertory Theatre, 1982-1986 (Folder 10.6)
    - Open Eye Theatre, 1983-1994 (Folder 10.7)
    - Phoenix Theatre Project – planning papers, 1952-1953 (Folder 10.8)
    - Phoenix Theatre, 1957-1982 (Folder 10.9)
    - Phoenix Theatre, 1964-1966 (Folder 10.10)
    - "Romeo and Juliet" / Lynchburg College, 1984 (Folder 10.11)
    - "R.U.R. (Rossum's Universal Robots),", 1994 (Folder 10.12)
    - Russian theatre materials, 1969-1972 (Folder 10.13)
    - St. Louis Municipal Opera, 1939-1940 (Folder 10.14)
    - "The Tall Kentuckian,", 1953 (Folder 10.15)
    - Theatre Development Fund, 1995 (Folder 10.16)
    - Theatre Incorporated, 1947-1959 (Folder 10.17)
    - Theatre Institute at Storm King, 1986-1990 (Folder 10.18)
  - Miscellaneous Subject Files
    - Bellagio Center / Rockefeller Foundation, 1970-1984 (Folder 11.1)
    - Bingham, Barry, 1986-1988 (Folder 11.2)
    - "Body Work" – Gaby Ford, circa 1993 (Folder 11.3)
    - China, 1980-1989 (Folder 11.4)
    - China, 1983-1985 (Folder 11.5)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica Films, 1964-1966, 1986 (Folder 11.6)
    - Hellenic Heritage Foundation, circa 1980-1989 (Folder 11.7)
    - German Visitors Program, 1964-1966 (Folder 11.8)
    - miscellaneous materials, [n.d.] (Folder 11.9)
- Series VI: Clippings and Printed Materials
  - brochure and newsletter, 1966, 1981 (Folder 11.10)
  - clipping from Russia, (very fragile) (Folder 11.11)
  - clippings – interviews and lectures (Folder 11.12)
  - clippings – interviews and lectures (Folder 11.13)
  - clippings – miscellaneous, 1934-1935; (very fragile) (Folder 11.14)
  - clippings – miscellaneous (Folder 11.15)
  - clippings – miscellaneous (Folder 11.16)
  - clippings – Phoenix Threatre (Folder 11.17)
  - clippings – Phoenix Threatre (Folder 11.18)
  - clippings – Phoenix Threatre (Folder 11.19)
  - clippings – Princeton University, 1927-1931 (Folder 12.1)
  - "Cultural Affairs,", 1970 (Folder 11.20)
  - "Duty Bound,", 1943 (Box 28)
  - Life Magazine, 26 March 1951; (very fragile) (Box 12)
  - Life Magazine, 12 April 1954; (2 copies) (Box 12)
  - Life Magazine, 24 May 1954; (fragile) (Box 12)
  - programs, 1975-1988 (Folder 12.2)
  - programs and playbills (Box 18)
  - theatre posters, (6 items) (Box 20)
  - working scripts (Box 28)
- Series VII: Photographic Materials
  - Photographs of or Including Norris Houghton
    - framed photo with Grace Houghton, circa 1915 (Box 23)
    - Norris Houghton, circa 1920–1925; (5 photos) (Folder 13.1)
    - Norris Houghton, circa 1926–1955; (5 photos) (Folder 13.2)
    - Norris Houghton, circa 1927-1960; (3 photos) (Folder 15.1)
    - Triangle Club of Princeton, 1929-1930 (Folder 16.2)
    - Norris Houghton, Barbara O'Niel, and unidentified performers, 1936-1937; (5 photos) (Folder 13.7)
    - Elitch's Garden Theatre, 1948; (2 photos) (Folder 15.2)
    - framed photo of Norris Houghton, circa 1960 (Box 25)
    - Norris Houghton and A. L. Rouse, 1984; (2 photos) (Folder 13.18)
    - Norris Houghton with unidentified man, n.d. (Folder 16.1)
  - Stage Productions Directed or Designed by Norris Houghton
    - "The Pijean,", 1930; (7 photos) (Folder 13.3)
    - "Othello," "Mr. Prin Passes By," "The Play's The Thing," "The Sea Gull," "Stopover,", 1930-1954; (6 photos) (Folder 13.4)
    - "Othello,", 1930 (Folders 15.12-15.13)
    - "Time Is A Dream,", 1930-1931 (Folders 15.14-15.15)
    - "Man And The Masses,", 1931; (8 photos) (Folder 13.5)
    - "The Dark Hours,", 1932; (2 photos) (Folder 13.6)
    - "Macbeth," "She Passed Through Lorraine," "Spring In Autumn," unidentified production, 1947-1948 / [n.d.]; (8 photos) (Folder 13.8)
    - "Macbeth,", 1947-1948 (Folders 15.3-15.11)
    - "Candida," "Haste To The Wedding," "Wife Insurance,", circa 1950-1960; (7 photos) (Folder 13.9)
    - "Billy Budd,", 1957; (9 photos) (Folder 13.10)
    - "Julius Caesar" – Actors Theatre of Louisville, 1982; (4 photos) (Folder 13.14)
    - "Julius Caesar" – Actors Theatre of Louisville, 1982; (4 slides) (Folder 13.15)
    - "Misalliance,", 1982-1983; (1 photo) (Folder 13.16)
    - "Holiday" – Heritage Repertory Theatre, 1983; (4 photos) (Folder 13.17)
  - Russian Performers and Productions, circa 1960-1972
    - identified performers and productions, (6 photos - identifications written on reverse] (Folder 14.1)
    - unidentified performers and productions, (6 photos) (Folder 14.2)
    - unidentified performers and productions, (5 photos) (Folder 14.3)
    - unidentified performers and productions, (4 photos) (Folder 14.4)
    - unidentified performers and productions, (5 photos) (Folder 14.5)
    - unidentified performers and productions, (5 photos) (Folder 14.6)
    - unidentified performers and productions, (5 photos) (Folder 14.7)
    - unidentified performers and productions, (5 photos) (Folder 14.8)
    - unidentified performers and productions, (6 photos) (Folder 14.9)
    - unidentified performers and productions, (3 photos) (Folder 15.3)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs
    - Gloucester School of the Little Theatre, 1930; (5 photos) (Folder 14.10)
    - Moscow, 1934-1935; (6 photos) (Folder 14.11)
    - "Hedda Gabler" unidentified stage set, 1940, [n.d.]; (4 photos) (Folder 14.12)
    - "Billy Bud" – cast members, circa 1957; (5 photos) (Folder 14.13)
    - "Billy Bud" – cast members, circa 1957; (5 photos) (Folder 14.14)
    - "Billy Bud" – cast members, circa 1957; (5 photos) (Folder 14.15)
    - "Richard III" – Warsaw, circa 1961; (6 photos) (Folder 14.16)
    - house photographs, 1962-1970; (2 photos) (Folder 14.17)
    - Korea, 1966; (3 photos) (Folder 14.18)
    - Missouri Repertory Theatre performers, 1981-1982; (5 photos) (Folder 13.11)
    - actors – Missouri Repertory Theatre performers, 1981-1982; (3 photos) (Folder 13.12)
    - actors – Missouri Repertory Theatre performers, 1981-1982; (6 photos) (Folder 13.13)
    - "Tall Ships of South Street,", 1982; (1 photo) (Folder 14.19)
    - actors – Heritage Repertory Theatre, 1983; (5 photos) (Folder 14.20)
    - actors – Heritage Repertory Theatre, 1983; (5 photos) (Folder 14.21)
    - China, 1986; (5 photos) (Folder 14.22)
    - China, 1986; (5 photos) (Folder 14.23)
    - Rebecca Dobson – American Kaleidoscope Theatre, [n.d.]; (1 photo) (Folder 14.24)
    - unidentified performers and prouctions, (4 photos) (Folder 14.25)
- Series VIII: Audio-Visual Materials
  - Audio Tapes
    - "Aspects Of The Contemporary American Theater" – reel 1, 1961 (Reel 1)
    - "Aspects Of The Contemporary American Theater" – reel 2, 1961 (Reel 2)
    - "Brecht" (Reel 3)
    - "Bretaigne, Windust" (Reel 4)
    - "Frances and Robert Crane" (Reel 5)
    - "Dalrymple, Whitehead, Henry Fonda" (Reel 6)
    - "Betty Fenner" (Reel 7)
    - "Higgins, Sullivan" (Reel 8)
    - "Huberth, Natwick, Altman, Fonda, and Smith" (Reel 9)
    - "McCormick, Dyer" (Reel 10)
    - "Quigley, Birnie, Cook" (Reel 11)
    - "Kent Smith and Henry Fonda", (tape broken) (Reel 12)
    - "Sullivan, Dorr, Pace" (Reel 13)
    - "Swope, Stewart" (Reel 14)
    - [unidentified] (Reel 15)
  - Motion Picture Films
    - "Playwrights In The Contemporary Theatre: Brecht and Piscator,", 1959 (Reel 1)
    - "Playwrights In The Contemporary Theatre, Introductory Lecture,", 1959; (very fragile) (Reel 2)
    - "Playwrights In The Contemporary Theatre: Miller, Odets,", 1959 (Reel 3)
- Series IX: Memorabilia
  - address and date books, 1934-1998 (Box 19)
  - autographed illustration, [n.d.] (Folder 26.1)
  - award certificates, 1953-1991; (5 items) (Box 20)
  - "Billy Budd" souvenir book, 1951 (Box 24)
  - honorary diplomas, 1983-1991; (4 items) (Box 20)
  - honorary diploma, 1987 (Box 26)
  - Life Magazine cover, 1954 (Folder 26.2)
  - portrait of Norris Houghton, [n.d.] (Box 16)
  - scrapbook, [n.d.] (Box 21)
  - scrapbook – Phoenix Theatre (Box 22)